Guide to the Rice University Dean of Students Office records, 1915-1974 UA 269
Woodson Research Center, Rice University, Houston, Texas
Rice University Dean of Students Office records
1915-1974
Woodson Research Center, Rice University, Houston, Texas https://library.rice.edu/woodson
Rice University
UA 269
9.5 Linear Feet (18 boxes)
Records created by or pertaining to the Dean of Students, including Honor Council cases and disciplinary records.
Biographical / Historical
The Rice University Dean of Students, later known as Dean of Undergraduates, is charged with assisting students with issues related to academics and advising, career services and extracurricular and social activities.
Scope and Contents
Corresondence, notes and other records of the daily business of the Dean of Students at Rice University.
Conditions Governing Access
This material is restricted. Contact Woodson Research Center for assistance in gaining access.
Conditions Governing Access
Stored off-site at the Library Service Center. Please request this material via woodson@rice.edu or call 713-348-2586.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Proctor's office; Dean of Undergraduate Affairs office; Dr. Higginbotham's office. Received 1974, 1980, 1981.
Index Terms
Subjects
Rice University -- History; Universities and colleges -- Administration; Universities and colleges
Document Types
documents
- Series I: Pre-"Dean of Students" materials, 1915-48; 153773
  - Absences (excused), n.d.; 153731 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Bridge Tournament, 1948; 153732 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Buildings and Grounds, 1946-48; 153733 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Camel cigarettes, 1948-49; 153734 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - The Council, 1947; 153735 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Elections, 1932-48; 153736 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Discipline-Rice/A&M students, 1946-48; 153737 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Executive Committee and faculty correspondence re: Student Affairs, 1947; 153738 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Halls-Room lists, 1947-47; 153739 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Gifts, 1947; 153740 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Health Committee, 1946-47; 153741 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Honor Council, 1915-16; 153742 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Honor Council, 1917-18; 153743 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Honor Council-Middleton case, 1917; 153744 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Honor Council minutes, correspondence, trial records, etc., 1921-39; 153745 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Honor Council, 1937-39; 153746 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Honor Council minutes, 1941-45; 153747 (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Honor Council, 1941-48; 153748 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Honor Council-Gunn, 1944; 153749 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Honor Council-Lowman, 1944; 153750 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Honor Council, 1944; 153751 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Honor Council, 1946-49; 153752 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Honor Council, 1946-48; 153753 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Honor Council, n.d.; 153754 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Inauguration (Houston), 1947; 153755 (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Office plans, 1947; 153756 (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Probation notes, 1940; 153757 (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Publications audit, 1927-30; 153758 (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - Questionnaires, 1946-48; 153759 (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - Rondelet, 1947; 153760 (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - Schedule Committee, 1946-48; 153761 (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - Social functions approvals, 1946-48; 153762 (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - Student Activities Committee, 1946-48; 153763 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Student Association constitution, by-laws, 1939; 153764 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Student Association constitution, 153765 (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Student Association/Council correspondence, 1946-48; 153766 (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Student elections (rules, petitions, etc.), 1932-48; 153767 (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Student organizations summaries, 1940-48; 153768 (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - Tag records, n.d.; 153769 (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - Traffic summary, 1946; 153770 (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - Transportation, 1946-48; 153771 (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - Women's Council, 1918-19; 153772 (Box 3, Folder 10)
- Series II: 1948-74, 153774
  - Dean Hugh Scott Cameron's appointment books, 1946-53; 153775 (Box 4)
  - AAUW College Faculty program, 1964-65; 153776 (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - Accidents, deaths, suicides, attempted suicides, 1961-73; 153777 (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - [Ad Hoc] Admissions Committee, 153778 (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - Admissions Committee, 1962-65; 153779 (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - Admissions interviews, 1962-63; 153780 (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - Applications-student jobs, 1949; 153781 (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - Army-Navy recruiting, 1963-64; 153782 (Box 5, Folder 7)
  - Athletics-Rice policy, 1963; 153783 (Box 5, Folder 8)
  - Bad debts-students, 1969-70; 153784 (Box 5, Folder 9)
  - Beiersdorf, Herman, 153785 (Box 5, Folder 10)
  - Blanket taxes, 1949; 153786 (Box 5, Folder 11)
  - Bomb threats, 1970-71; 153787 (Box 5, Folder 12)
  - Bridge Tournament-Intercollegiate, 1949-50; 153788 (Box 5, Folder 13)
  - [Approved] Budget, Dean of Undergraduate Affairs, 1970-71; 154271 (Box 5, Folder 14)
  - Budget estimate, Dean of Undergraduate Affairs, 1970-71; 154272 (Box 5, Folder 15)
  - Budgets, 1974-82; 154273 (Box 5, Folder 16)
  - Buildings and Grounds, 1963; 154291 (Box 5, Folder 17)
  - Business Manager, 1964-65; 154292 (Box 5, Folder 18)
  - Cases, misc., 1972-73; 154293 (Box 5, Folder 19)
  - Cases, misc., 1974; 154294 (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - Catalogue revisions, 1948-49; 154295 (Box 6, Folder 2)
  - Chaille Rice Literary Society, 1962-65; 154296 (Box 6, Folder 3)
  - Charges, dormitory rooms, 1949; 154297 (Box 6, Folder 4)
  - Charities, 1948-49; 154298 (Box 6, Folder 5)
  - Chesterfield student representative, 1948; 154299 (Box 6, Folder 6)
  - College Women's Club, 1961-62; 154300 (Box 6, Folder 7)
  - Committee on Student Health, 1973-76; 154301 (Box 6, Folder 8)
  - Committee on Student Health, 1980-81; 154302 (Box 6, Folder 9)
  - Conference-Informal Dean's, 1948; 154303 (Box 6, Folder 10)
  - Conference-Informal Dean's, 1949; 154304 (Box 6, Folder 11)
  - Correspondence/budget, Security Dept., 1969-70; 154305 (Box 6, Folder 12)
  - Correspondence, Campanile, 1965-69; 154306 (Box 6, Folder 13)
  - Correspondence, general, 1949; 154307 (Box 6, Folder 14)
  - Correspondence, general, 1973-75; 154308 (Box 6, Folder 15)
  - Correspondence, Women's Affairs, 1960-61; 154309 (Box 6, Folder 16)
  - Courses and enrollment, 1969; 154310 (Box 6, Folder 17)
  - Courses-schedules, 1948-51; 154311 (Box 7, Folder 1)
  - Culmore Hall, 1963-64; 154312 (Box 7, Folder 2)
  - Deaning-McBride (Associate Dean of Students), 1948-58; 154313 (Box 7, Folder 3)
  - Discipline, 1950-56; 154314 (Box 7, Folder 4)
  - Discipline, 1956-58; 154315 (Box 7, Folder 5)
  - Discipline, 1958-59; 154316 (Box 7, Folder 6)
  - Discipline, 1959-60; 154317 (Box 7, Folder 7)
  - Discipline, 1960-61; 154318 (Box 8, Folder 1-2)
  - Discipline, 1961-62; 154320 (Box 8, Folder 3-4)
  - Discipline-Women, 1962-63; 154339 (Box 8, Folder 5)
  - Discipline, 1962-63; 154340 (Box 8, Folder 6)
  - Discipline, 1963-64; 154341 (Box 9, Folder 1)
  - Discipline, 1964-65; 154342 (Box 9, Folder 2)
  - Discipline, 1965-66; 154343 (Box 9, Folder 3)
  - Discipline, 1966-67; 154344 (Box 9, Folder 4)
  - Discipline, 1967-68; 154345 (Box 9, Folder 5)
  - Discipline, 1968-69; 154346 (Box 9, Folder 6)
  - Discipline, 1969-70; 154347 (Box 10, Folder 1)
  - Discipline, 1970-71; 154348 (Box 10, Folder 2)
  - Discipline, 1971-72; 154349 (Box 10, Folder 3)
  - Discipline, 1972-73; 154350 (Box 10, Folder 4)
  - Discipline, 1973-74; 154351 (Box 10, Folder 5)
  - Election returns, 1948-50; 154352 (Box 11, Folder 1)
  - Elizabeth Baldwin Literary Society, 1960-64, 1971; 154353 (Box 11, Folder 2)
  - Employment, colleges, 1969; 154354 (Box 11, Folder 3)
  - Employment, Registrar's Office, 1969; 154355 (Box 11, Folder 4)
  - Esquire, 1949; 154356 (Box 11, Folder 5)
  - Faculty committees, 1964-65; 154357 (Box 11, Folder 6)
  - Faculty Council and Faculty Meeting minutes, 1965-68; 154358 (Box 11, Folder 7)
  - Faculty Meeting and minutes, 1964-65; 154359 (Box 11, Folder 8)
  - Faculty [misc.] notices, 1959-65; 154360 (Box 11, Folder 9)
  - Faculty rating poll, 1950; 154361 (Box 11, Folder 10)
  - Field House, c. 1950; 154362 (Box 11, Folder 11)
  - Financial Aid student policy, 1964-69; 154363 (Box 11, Folder 12)
  - Forms, Registrar's Office, 1970; 154364 (Box 11, Folder 13)
  - Freeman, Charles E. case, 1969; 154365 (Box 11, Folder 14)
  - GI students, 1949-50; 154366 (Box 11, Folder 15)
  - Grade distribution report, 1969-70; 154367 (Box 11, Folder 16)
  - Halls and dormitory investigations, 1948-49; 154368 (Box 11, Folder 17)
  - Halls-assignments, concessions, 1949-50; 154369 (Box 11, Folder 18)
  - Halls-disciplinary, 1949-50; 154370 (Box 11, Folder 19)
  - Halls-regulations, 1948-50; 154371 (Box 11, Folder 20)
  - Halls-room lists, 1948-49; 154372 (Box 11, Folder 21)
  - Halls-washateria, 1948; 154373 (Box 11, Folder 22)
  - Hazen Conference, 1950; 154374 (Box 12, Folder 1)
  - Health Center, 1981-82; 154375 (Box 12, Folder 2)
  - Health Services, 1971-73; 154376 (Box 12, Folder 3)
  - Health Services, 1972-77; 154377 (Box 12, Folder 4)
  - Health Services budgets, 1974-78; 154378 (Box 12, Folder 5)
  - Health Services contracts, 1978-80; 154379 (Box 12, Folder 6)
  - Health Services corresp. re: Fullen, Night Clinic, 1979-80; 154380 (Box 12, Folder 7)
  - Health Services operations, 1979-80; 154381 (Box 12, Folder 8)
  - Health Services reports, 1970s; 154382 (Box 12, Folder 9)
  - Honor Council, 1948-50; 154383 (Box 12, Folder 10)
  - Honor Council, misc., 1948-59; 154384 (Box 12, Folder 11)
  - Honor Council, 1951-55; 154385 (Box 13, Folder 1)
  - Honor Council, 1953-56; 154386 (Box 13, Folder 2)
  - Honor Council, 1956-57; 154387 (Box 13, Folder 3)
  - Honor Council, 1957-62; 154388 (Box 13, Folder 4)
  - Honor Council, 1962-65; 154389 (Box 13, Folder 5)
  - Honor Council, 1965-68; 154390 (Box 14, Folder 1)
  - Honor Council, 1968-72; 154391 (Box 14, Folder 2)
  - Honor Council, 1972-74; 154392 (Box 14, Folder 3)
  - Hoffman Affair, 1970; 154393 (Box 14, Folder 4)
  - House: Graduate Students, 1962-63; 154394 (Box 14, Folder 5)
  - Housing off-campus, 1962-65; 154395 (Box 14, Folder 6)
  - Kratzenstein, 1971; 154396 (Box 14, Folder 7)
  - Literary societies, general, 154397 (Box 14, Folder 8)
  - MIT Symposium (American Women in Science & Engineering), 1964; 154398 (Box 14, Folder 9)
  - Navy, 1948-49; 154399 (Box 14, Folder 10)
  - Owen Wister Literary Society, 1950, 60-64; 154400 (Box 14, Folder 11)
  - Pallas Athene Literary Society, 1960-64; 154401 (Box 14, Folder 12)
  - Parking, 1948-49; 154402 (Box 14, Folder 13)
  - Pepsi-Cola Awards, 1948; 154403 (Box 15, Folder 1)
  - Personnel work, 1950; 154404 (Box 15, Folder 2)
  - Psychiatric Services, 1974-79; 154405 (Box 15, Folder 3)
  - Publications, 1969; 154406 (Box 15, Folder 4)
  - Public Relations, 1949; 154407 (Box 15, Folder 5)
  - Questionnaires, 1948-50; 154408 (Box 15, Folder 6)
  - Radio station KOWL, 1969; 154409 (Box 15, Folder 7)
  - R Association, 1948; 154410 (Box 15, Folder 8)
  - Registrar's Office, 1969-70; 154411 (Box 15, Folder 9)
  - Registrar's Report, 1969-70; 154412 (Box 15, Folder 10)
  - Registrar's Withdrawal Report, 1969-70; 154413 (Box 15, Folder 11)
  - Religious activities, 154414 (Box 15, Folder 12)
  - Report to the President, Dean of UG Affairs, 1967-68; 154415 (Box 15, Folder 13)
  - Residential colleges, 1969-70; 154416 (Box 15, Folder 14)
  - Residential Colleges reports, 1969-70; 154417 (Box 15, Folder 15)
  - Responsibility-student, 1968; 154418 (Box 15, Folder 16)
  - Responsibilities, students, faculty, staff on campus policy, 1969; 154419 (Box 15, Folder 17)
  - Rice University Studies, 1962-63; 154420 (Box 15, Folder 18)
  - ROTC misc., 1970; 154421 (Box 15, Folder 19)
  - Sarah Lane Literary Society, 1960-64; 154422 (Box 15, Folder 20)
  - Scholarship forms, n.d.; 154423 (Box 15, Folder 21)
  - Scholarships-Rice, 1948-49; 154424 (Box 15, Folder 22)
  - Science/Engineering in Houston, 1969; 154425 (Box 15, Folder 23)
  - Security Dept., 1970; 154426 (Box 15, Folder 24)
  - Selective Service System, 1969; 154427 (Box 15, Folder 25)
  - Service awards, 1963; 154428 (Box 16, Folder 1)
  - Social functions approvals, 1948-50; 154429 (Box 16, Folder 2)
  - Songs, 1948; 154430 (Box 16, Folder 3)
  - Space allotments-university, 1969-70; 154431 (Box 16, Folder 4)
  - Statistics, women students, 1964-65; 154432 (Box 16, Folder 5)
  - Students, 1970; 154433 (Box 16, Folder 6)
  - Students accepted, 1950-51; 154434 (Box 16, Folder 7)
  - Student Activities Committee, 1948-51; 154435 (Box 16, Folder 8)
  - Student Activities Committee, 1951-53; 154436 (Box 16, Folder 9)
  - Student Activities Committee, 1954-55; 154437 (Box 16, Folder 10)
  - Student Activities Committee, 1955-58; 154438 (Box 16, Folder 11)
  - Student Activities Committee supplementary material, 1949-57; 154439 (Box 17, Folder 1)
  - Student Affairs Committee, 1963-65; 154440 (Box 17, Folder 2)
  - Student Alcoholic Beverages Policy, 1969; 154441 (Box 17, Folder 3)
  - Student Association/Council correspondence, 1948-49; 154442 (Box 17, Folder 4)
  - Student Council minutes, 1948-50; 154443 (Box 17, Folder 5)
  - Student Council minutes, 1950-52; 154444 (Box 17, Folder 6)
  - Student Council minutes, 1952-55; 154445 (Box 17, Folder 7)
  - Student Council minutes, 1955-57; 154446 (Box 17, Folder 8)
  - Student Council minutes, 1957-61 & Intercollege Council, 1957-58; 154447 (Box 17, Folder 9)
  - Student drug use-Off Campus policy, 1967; 154448 (Box 18, Folder 1)
  - Student drug use-On Campus policy, 1969; 154449 (Box 18, Folder 2)
  - Student housing-colleges, 1969; 154450 (Box 18, Folder 3)
  - Student organizations-social functions rules, 1962-63; 154451 (Box 18, Folder 4)
  - Student organizations, 1948-50; 154452 (Box 18, Folder 5)
  - Student publications-History of Control Policy, 1969; 154453 (Box 18, Folder 6)
  - Study group-Belgrade Proposal, 1970; 154454 (Box 18, Folder 7)
  - Suspensions or Honor Council violations, 1963-77; 154455 (Box 18, Folder 8)
  - Texas Women's University, general, 1962-64; 154456 (Box 18, Folder 9)
  - Texas Women's University, 1963-64; 154457 (Box 18, Folder 10)
  - Texas Women's University, 1964; 154458 (Box 18, Folder 11)
  - Texas Women's University, 1964-65; 154459 (Box 18, Folder 12)
  - Texas Women's University discipline, 1963-65; 154460 (Box 18, Folder 13)
  - Thresher, 1969; 154461 (Box 18, Folder 14)
  - Undergraduate Affairs, Committee on, 1965-66; 154462 (Box 18, Folder 15)
  - Undergraduate Affairs, Committee on, 1967-68; 154463 (Box 18, Folder 16)
  - Wells Design re-upholstery, 1964-65; 154464 (Box 18, Folder 17)